nationalexpress.com 2015-06-19

# Privacy and Cookies | National Express Coaches

**1 st December 2011 Version**

## 1\. About our policy

This privacy policy indicates National Express' policies regarding the collection and use of visitor information, and our use of cookies and similar technologies, in relation to our website [www.nationalexpress.com](http://www.nationalexpress.com/), and our email and sms marketing activities.

This privacy policy will inform you about what data collection methods (including cookies) we use, what information is collected by our website, how this information will be used, with whom the information may be shared, and your rights.

By visiting our website you consent to our processing of your information as set out in this privacy policy and to the use of the technologies listed.

If you have any requests or queries, or would like to be removed from our mailing list, then please [click here to contact us](http://www.nationalexpress.com/coach/ContactUs/index.cfm), or alternatively, write to: Data Protection Officer, National Express Group PLC, National Express House, Birmingham Coach Station, Mill Lane, Digbeth, Birmingham B5 6DD.

## 2\. Collection and use of visitor information

 **2.1 What data collection methods (includ** i **ng cookies) do we use on our website?**

We use a range of data collection methods and technologies on our website, which we use to collect data for the purposes of transactions with you, gathering statistics and analytics on our website traffic and users' behaviour, evaluating our marketing effectiveness, requesting user feedback, and to improve our website and customer satisfaction.  We also enable third party cookies and other technologies through our website, such as those used by advertisers.   These technologies place [cookies](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie) and [JavaScripts](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JavaScript) in your web browser cache, and may use [IFRAMES](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTML_element#Frames) or other technologies to show third party content. All modern web browsers allow cookies and JavaScripts to be disabled through browser security settings, but parts of our website may not work correctly if your security settings are set too high.  At the time of writing, the following technologies are used on our website:-

 **Forms**

| 

We collect information from you that you enter into any form (e.g. a text entry field) on our website. We receive this information when you submit the form (such as when you submit a journey query or make a ticket purchase).  
  
---|---  
  
 **National Express' own cookies**

| 

We place our own first party cookies and other data files in your web browser cache for the purposes of operating our website, including session cookies necessary for the registration, purchase or other processes on our website (our cookies are currently named CFID and CFTOKEN at the time of writing). [Click here for details of the cookies used on our website.](http://www.nationalexpress.com/coach/ourservice/cookies.aspx)  
  
 **VE Interactive**

| 

We use the [VE Interactive](http://www.veinteractive.com/) service to monitor when our visitors start, but do not complete, a transaction with us, to enable us to better support our visitors. The service captures contact details (such as name and e-mail address) as soon as they are typed into a form on our website, and this data is used by us to send a follow-up support and marketing e-mail, if our visitor does not subsequently complete the transaction on our website. For more information see also the [VE Interactive Privacy Policy.](http://www.veinteractive.com/privacy.php) This service involves the storage of third party JavaScript files and cookies on your computer.  
  
 **ClickTale**

| 

We use the [ClickTale](http://www.clicktale.com/) web analytics service. We use this service to collect fine detail information about how our visitors use each page on our website, and to make improvements to the user experience on our website. The ClickTale service records taps, clicks, gestures, cursor movements, scrolling, and key presses and information entered into forms, in real-time, even if a form is not submitted. We do not use ClickTale to collect any personal information, including passwords. ClickTale does not track use of any websites that do not use the ClickTale service. The information collected will also be used by ClickTale. For more information see the [ClickTale Privacy Policy.](http://www.clicktale.com/privacy_service.aspx) You can choose to disable the ClickTale service for your web browser here. This service involves the storage of third party JavaScript files and cookies on your computer (which at the time of writing are named bookingWidgetClicktale.js and WRc5.js).  
  
 **Google Analytics**

| 

We use the [Google Analytics](http://www.google.com/analytics/)service to collect and analyse information about how our visitors use our website. The service collects information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to our website, where visitors have come to the website from, and the pages on our website visited. We use this information to compile statistical and other information about the website in the form of reports. The information collected will also used by Google. For more information see the [Google Analytics Privacy Overview.](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html) The service places a JavaScript and several cookies on your web browser to operate (currently named ga.js and __utma, __utmb, __utmz, WRUID, and WRIgnore at the time of writing).  
  
 **Kampyle**

| 

We use the [Kampyle](http://www.kampyle.com/) feedback form service. This service allows us to ask users for feedback through pop-up feedback forms on our website, which we use to provide improved customer service. For more information see also the [Kampyle Privacy Policy.](http://www.kampyle.com/privacy-policy?utm_medium=FF&utm_source=9144165&utm_campaign=privacy) The service may place a JavaScript and cookies on your web browser to operate.  
  
 **Scorecard Research**

| 

We use the [ScorecardResearch](http://www.scorecardresearch.com/Home.aspx) service to study and report on Internet trends and behavior. ScorecardResearch conducts research by collecting Internet web browsing data and then uses that data to help show how people use the Internet, what they like about it, and what they don't. The service uses web tagging by deploying a special code throughout our website. The service places several cookies on your web browser to operate (currently named UID and UIDR at the time of writing).  
  
 **Social Networking**

| 

We use the [ShareThis](http://sharethis.com/) service to provide social network sharing functionality (which at the time of writing is provided through a linked third party webpage which places the cookies stid and uset in your web browser cache, and also a JavaScript).  
  
 **Cheetahmail**

| 

We use the Cheetahmail service to collect information on how customers interact with our emails, such uses include conversion tracking between email activity and online sales The cookies that Cheetahmail set do not contain any personally identifiable information such as name or e-mail address. Cheetahmail cookies may also be combined with the use of web beacons. A web beacon is an invisible image with a line of code, also called a clear gif, which is placed within an email message or on a web page. The reasons for use of a web beacon include:

  * To sense whether a recipient can receive html email or only receive text email

  * Whether the email recipient has opened the message, and whether that email message was opened successive times.

Web beacons do not create, modify or delete files on a user's machine. They are not executable and cannot be used to deliver dangerous content, such as a virus. Web beacons are connected to help identify a particular email recipient, who can then be used by CheetahMail clients for future reference when selecting and sending additional email.  
  
 **Advertising**

| 

We use a range of services in connection with advertising, including selling advertising space on our website (enabling third party adverts to appear on our website), and also to track when our website has been visited from an advert of ours shown on a third party website (e.g. a click through).

Third party advertising networks purchase advertising space on behalf of their customers, and manage the performance of those adverts. Third party adverts may originate from a third party webpage, embedded into our website using an [IFRAME](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTML_element#Frames) or other technology.

These networks and services place third party JavaScripts and cookies in your web browser cache to enable management of adverts and click-throughs, including tracking of views and clicks. As at the time of writing, the services and third party advertising networks we use include the following:-

[Google Ad Services](http://www.google.co.uk/ads/) (which at the time of writing places a JavaScript called conversion.js in your web browser cache).

[DoubleClick](http://www.google.com/doubleclick/publishers/index.html) which is a service operated by Google to manage advertising sales (which at the time of writing places a JavaScript called id in your web browser cache).

[RockYou](http://rockyou.com/ry/mediahome) which is a games advertising network (which at the time of writing places a cookie called _uix in your web browser cache).

[MathTag](http://mathtag.com/) is general advertising network (which at the time of writing places cookies called uuid, ts and mt_mop in your web browser cache).

[Media6Degrees](http://m6d.com/info/privacy-policy/) which we use to target our advertising by collecting information about visitors to our website, which is use to develop general customer profiles (which at the time of writing places cookies called orblb, clid, sglst, rdrlst, ipinfo and acs in your web browser cache).

[RightMedia/Yieldmanager](http://rightmedia.com/) is an advertising network from Yahoo.com for trading ad space (which at the time of writing places tracking cookies called bh, uid, B and BX in your web browser cache).

[Lotame/w55c.net](http://www.lotame.com/) is an advertising network (which at the time of writing places tracking cookies called wfivefivec in your web browser cache).

[Tribalfusion](http://www.tribalfusion.com/) is an advertising network (which at the time of writing places tracking cookies called ANON_ID in your web browser cache).  
  
 **Wtp101**

| 

wtp101.com places tracking cookies called tuuid, s and synced in your web browser cache.  
  
 **2.2 What information do we collect?**

We will collect name, address, log-in, transaction, payment and other information which our visitors enter into forms completed and submitted through our website.

Our technologies above also capture information about your use of our website, including where you visited our website from and click-throughs, what pages you visit, your use of each page (taps, clicks, gestures, cursor movements, scrolling, and key presses, and information entered into forms), and your feedback.

We also collect your browser information, including your browser make (e.g. Internet Explorer, Firefox, Safari, Opera, Chrome), your operating system (e.g. Microsoft Windows, OSX, Android), your IP address (a unique identifier allocated to your computer for your connection to the internet), and your domain name. 

Our own and third party cookies and other technologies will also be used to collect information to track visits to our website and advertising.  Please see further Paragraph 2.1 ' _What data collection methods (including cookies) do we use on our website?_ ' above.

By providing your email address you give consent for National Express (including Eurolines) to contact you via email for marketing purposes.

 **2.3 How will this information be used?**

We respect your privacy and may use your information:-

  * to process any registration for an account on our website and for the subsequent administration of that account;
  * to process enquiries through our website;
  * to process any ticket purchases or other transactions through our website;
  * to log various usage and statistical information about your use of our website;
  * to administer the website and gather broad demographic information about users of the site;
  * to keep you informed about National Express Limited and our services;
  * to send you offers and promotions from National Express Limited and third parties, including details of special offers, promotions, new products and services;
  * to advise of changes to our website;
  * to improve our website, and to customise our website for our visitors; and
  * to track and manage advertising.

If you prefer not to receive any further marketing communications from us, you can opt out at any time.  See further Paragraph 3.3 ' _Opt-out Procedure_ ' below.

 **2.4 Who will we share your information with?**

We may disclose information to:

  * our regulators, lawyers and auditors;
  * other companies within our group;
  * persons where required by law under a court order or subpoena;
  * third party service providers or agents acting on our behalf; and
  * providers of any of the services and technologies identified in Paragraph 2.1 ' _What data collection methods (including cookies) do we use on our website?_ ' above and advertising networks.

## 3\. Your rights

 **3.1 Retention**

Personal information will be retained for as long as the purpose for which it was collected continues, in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. It will then be destroyed although copies may be retained if required to satisfy our legal, regulatory or accounting requirements.

 **3.2 Access Rights**

Under the Data Protection Act 1998, you are entitled to a copy of any personal information we hold on you, but we may charge a fee of no more than £10 for providing this information.

To obtain a copy of any personal information we hold on you write to: Customer Relations Team, National Express Limited, Floor 14, 1 Hagley Road, Birmingham B16 8TG.

 **3.3 Opt-Out Procedure**

For some types of marketing communications, our site may provide an opt-in and opt-out facility so that you only receive those communications if you choose to. Whenever we send you a communication we will also give you the opportunity to request your details to be removed from our marketing list. At any time you can access your account and change your status indicating whether you want to opt-in or opt-out of receiving those communications.   Or you can write to us at National Express Limited, National Express House, Mill Lane, Digbeth, Birmingham B5 6DD.

If you do not want to receive emails from National Express please write to us at 1 Hagley Road, Birmingham, West Midlands, B16 8TG, or call us on 08717 818181 and state your wish to be removed from the email list. Alternatively customers can unsubscribe by clicking an unsubscribe link that will feature in all emails sent by National Express.

 **3.4 Changes / Modification to personal information**

You may make a request to us to change or modify any inaccuracies in your personal information at any time free of charge. Further if you are aware at any time that any of the personal information that you have given to us has changed, then please let us know at the earliest opportunity of the changes that need to be made to your personal information. If you would like guidance on how to change the information that we hold on you please [click here to contact us](http://www.nationalexpress.com/coach/ContactUs/index.cfm), or alternatively, write to: Data Protection Officer, National Express Group PLC, National Express House, Birmingham Coach Station, Mill Lane, Digbeth, Birmingham B5 6DD.

## 4\. General Information

 **4.1 Changes to this Privacy Policy**

If we change this policy, we will post the new policy on our home page. If the change means that we will use your information differently, we will notify you. You may accept the change of use, or if you do not, we will continue to use your information in accordance with the policy under which it was collected.

 **4.2 Keeping your data secure**

We will use technical and organisational measures to safeguard your personal information, for example:

  * all information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers;
  * any payment transactions will be encrypted; and
  * access to your account on this website is controlled by password and username which are unique to you.

Whilst we will use reasonable efforts to safeguard your personal information, you acknowledge that the use of the internet is not entirely secure and for this reason we cannot guarantee the security or integrity of any personal information which are transferred from you or to you via the internet.

 **4.3 Our Pledge to You**

We pledge our intention to meet our obligations under this privacy policy statement, and to comply with the requirements of the Data Protection Act 1998.

 **4.4 Other Websites**

Our website may contain links to the websites of other companies that are outside of our control. These websites are not covered by this privacy policy. If you access other sites through our website then the operators of these sites may collect information from you which will be used by them in accordance with their own privacy policies, which may differ from ours.

 **4.5 Legal Entity**

National Express Limited is a company registered in England and Wales, with company number 232767, whose registered office is National Express Group PLC, National Express House, Birmingham Coach Station, Mill Lane, Digbeth, Birmingham B5 6DD. National Express Limited is a subsidiary of National Express Group PLC, registered number 2590560.  National Express Limited is the 'data controller' for the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998.

 **4.6 Copyright**

All copyright, database rights, design rights, and all intellectual property rights in and to all text and graphics their selection and arrangement, and all mark up/layout/scripts, software compilations, underlying source (hyper text mark up language and scripts) and all other materials on this web site belong solely and absolutely to National Express Limited.

No part of our web site can be reproduced in any form whatsoever whether electronically or otherwise without our prior written consent other than temporarily in the course of using our web site or to keep a record of a transaction entered into using this web site.

Copyright © National Express Limited 2007 to 2013.

 **4.7 Liability Disclaimer**

We disclaim and exclude any duty of care which we may owe you in respect of the information on this web site. Your reliance on this web site and your use of this web site is entirely at your own risk. Nothing on this web site constitutes an offer to enter into any contract, and all orders for tickets are subject to acceptance by National Express Limited. We exclude all warranties, terms and conditions implied by law in relation to this web site.

You may not rely on any statement or representation in the web site, and when you buy tickets from National Express Limited you agree that you have not relied on any statement or representation in this web site.

We do not exclude our liability for fraudulent misrepresentation.

We shall have no liability for any loss or damage you suffer as a result of relying on any fact or statement that prove to be incorrect.

This web site contains hyper links to web sites operated by third parties. If you activate this hyper link you will leave the National Express Limited web site and National Express Limited have no control over and will not accept any liability whatsoever in respect of the material in any web site which is not on the National Express Limited web site
